Burr Family Papers Ms B20
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Burr Family Papers
1743-1955
Ms B20
Fairfield Museum and History Center
7.0 Linear feet 23 boxes 10 oversize items Approximately 2,000 items
A collection of papers from various generations of the Burr family of Fairfield, CT.
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
The Burr family settled in Fairfield in the 1600's. The Burrs in this collection were town officials, farmers, storekeepers, sea farers and business people.
Among the more distinguished family members were Thaddeus Burr (1736-1801) at whose house John Hancock was married and Aaron Burr (1756-1836) whose father moved from Fairfield to Newark, NJ.
Burr Family Members
Thaddeus Burr, 1735-1801
George Burr, b. 1740
Ebenezer Burr III, b. 1750's
Peter Burr, 1754-1816
Nathaniel Burr, Jr., b. 1767
Caroline Burr, b. 1798
Eben Burr, 1798-1873
David Burr, 1826-1866
Magdalen Grostephen Burr (wife of David), 1831-1908
William Burr, 1831-1914
James O. Burr, 1859-1913
David A. Burr, 1864-1923
Emma Josephine Burr, 1860-1901
William O. Burr, 1876-1953
Aretta Burr Sherwood (wife of William O.), 1868-1956
Lillian Burr, b. 1882
Florence Burr (Mrs. Philo Shelton), 1893-1976
Theodore B. Burr, b. 1899
Raymonde Pezard Burr, b. 1895
Theodosia Burr Thomas Lyon
Alice A. Burr (wife of Frederick)
Anna F. Burr
Eben Burr, b. 1901
Ephraim Burr
Peter Burr
Henry S. Burr
William T. Burr
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of 23 boxes and 10 oversize items. Box I contains deeds, probate records and writs. The rest of the boxes have been arranged chronologically and by family member where possible. Box II is an assortment of family members.
Box III and V pertain to David Burr and his wife Magdalen while Box IV contains seafaring type materials including Bowditch's Practical Navigator. Box VI contains William Burr's papers and Boxes VII and VIII hold James O. Burr's papers, consisting mostly of letters from "Mame". Box IX has the papers of Josie, David A. and Emma Josephine BUrr.
William O. Burr's papers make up Boxes X and XI and include Fairfield Tercentenary papers as well as a "phrenological character" of W. O. His wife Aretta's papers are in Box XII as are Eunice Dennie Burr and Harry Hill Sherwood. Papers from Lillian Burr's college days at Mt. Holyoke can be found in Boxes XIII and XIV.
Box XV contains Florence Burr Shelton's papers and some photos. Papers belonging to Theodore B., Raymonde Pezard and Theodosia Burr are in Box XVI and include interesting World War I related items. Box XVII is made up of miscellaneous items but of particular note are letters written to Florence A. Wright (Mrs. George Wright) from "Da Da" while both traveled with the Elsie DeWolf theatre company.
Box XVIII holds various account books while Box XIX contains family photos and postcards. Copies of Howard Burr's papers are in Box XX while Box XXI holds Mrs. Frederick A. Burr (Alice) papers. William T. Burr's items, including his Civil Air Patrol papers, are in Box XXII while Fred A. Burr's papers are in Box XXIII.
Related Archival Materials note
Other Burr Family material can be found in Ms B24 (letters from World War I), Ms B53 (A DAR scrapbook) and Ms B25 (World War I scrapbook).
Burr, Alva; Burr, Anna F.; Burr, Caroline, b. 1798; Burr, David A., 1864-1932; Burr, David, 1826-1866; Burr, Eben, 1798-1873; Burr, Eben, b. 1901; Burr, Ebenezer III; Burr, Emma Josephine, 1860-1901; Burr, Ephraim; Burr, Eunice Dennie; Burr, Frederick A.; Burr, George, b. 1740; Burr, Henry S.; Burr, James O., 1859-1913; Burr, Josie; Burr, Lillian, b. 1882; Burr, Magdalen Grostephen, 1831-1908; Burr, Nathaniel, Jr., b. 1767; Burr, Nehemiah; Burr, Peter, 1754-1816; Burr, Peter; Burr, Raymonde Pezard, b. 1895; Burr, Thaddeus, 1735-1801; Burr, Theodore B., b. 1899; Burr, Theodosia; Burr, William O., 1876-1953; Burr, William T.; Burr, William, 1831-1914; Burr, Zalmon, 1869-1832; Shelton, Florence Burr, 1893-1976; Sherwood, Aretta Burr, 1868-1956; Sherwood, Henry Hill, 1870-1937; Account books--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Churches--Connecticut.; Correspondence.; Deeds--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Fairfield(Conn.); Merchants--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Probate records--Connecticut--Fairfield; Receipts(financial records); School notebooks; Ships; Writs--Connecticut.
- Box I--Deeds, 9 Folders
  - Deeds, 1752-1794; Folder A; 23 items
    - Ephraim Burr from Isaac Jennings (photo), 1743
    - Town of Fairfield from Samuel Sturgis and Thad Burr, 1752
    - Nathaniel Burr from David Burr, 1767
    - Ebenezer Burr from Ephraim and Abagail Burr, 1769
    - Peter Burr from Ephraim and Abagail Burr, 1769
    - Ozias Burr from Hephzabah Burr, 1774
    - Ozias Burr from Isaac Edwards, 1783
    - Ozias Burr from Samuel Odell, 1783
    - Ozias Burr from Elijah Burr, 1786
    - Ebenezer Burr from Peter Hendrick, 1788
    - Ozias Burr from Richard HUbbell and Josiah Lacey, 1788
    - Ozias Burr from Nehemiah and Elizabeth Budington, 1788, 1795, 1796; 3 items
    - Ozias Burr from Zachariah Sherwood, 1789
    - Ozias Burr from Mary Bertram, 1789
    - Ozias Burr from Silas Hawley, 1789
    - Ozias Burr from Jonathan Bulkley (estate), 1791
    - Ozias Burr from Abijah Morehouse, 1797
    - Ozias Burr from John Burr III, 1791
    - Ozias Burr from David Hobby, 1797
    - Peter Burr from Hannah Bulkley, 1793
    - Peter Burr from Jason Gold, 1794
  - Deeds, 1794-1847; Folder B; 22 items
    - Amose Burr from Ozias Burr, 1794
    - Ozias Burr from Moses Sherwood, 1795
    - Ozias Burr from Dovid Coley, 1795
    - Ozias Burr from Richard Hubbell, 1795
    - Ozias Burr from Josiah Lacey, 1796
    - Aaron Burr from Elijah Burr, 1806
    - Ozias Burr from Amos Merriman, 1812
    - Joseph Couch from Elizabeth Burr, 1812
    - Edad Gould from Zalmon and Polly Burr, 1814
    - Louis J. Burr from Jonathan Willson, 1816
    - Eben Burr from Ellen Wilson, 1820
    - Robert Knapp from Jesse Burr, 1821
    - Eben Burr from Ebenezer Burr, 1822
    - Eben Burr from Robert Knapp, 1827
    - Eben Burr from Abijah Silliman, 1828
    - Eben Burr from Alfred Hayes, 1834
    - Eben Burr from Benjamin Meeker, 1839
    - Eben Burr from Lyman Wilcox, et al., 1842
    - Eben Burr from Ellen Bennett, 1843
    - Eben Burr from George Robinson, 1843
    - Eben Burr from Ransom Phillips, 1847
    - Eben Burr from N.Y., N.H. Railroad Co., 1847
  - Deeds, 1850-1889; Folder C; 24 items
    - Eben Burr from Moses I. Tailer, 1850
    - Eben Burr from John H. Gorman, 1850
    - Hannah A. Wakeman from Sally Wakeman, 1853
    - Eben Burr from Charles Withrop, 1854
    - William Burr from Lyman and Sally Wilcox, 1855
    - William Burr from Benjamin Wakeman, 1855
    - William Burr from Eben and Hannah Burr, 1857
    - Luke Ashe from Eben and Hannah Burr, 1865
    - William Burr from Wilson Turney, 1865
    - William Burr from Julia Wakeman, 1868
    - William Burr from H. and Mary A. Burr, 1868
    - William Burr from Ephraim H. Burr, 1869
    - William Burr from Ebenezer and Hannah A. Burr, 1870
    - William Burr from Alfred Wilson, et al., 1870
    - Wlliam Burr from Levi Turney, 1870
    - William Burr from Henry L. Knapp, 1871
    - William Burr from Sara Morehouse, et al., 1874
    - Willaim Burr from John and Harriet Van Duyn, 1877
    - Aurelia Burr from Lizette Hyde, 1879
    - William Burr from Hannah A. Burr, 1883
    - William Burr from Thomas McKeon, 1884
    - William Burr from Sarah E. Kelly, 1885
      - Mary C. Meeker from Aurelia C. Burr, 1888
    - William Burr from Hannah A. Burr, 1888
    - William Burr from Oliver B. Jennings, 1889
  - Deeds, 1910-1955; Folder D; 40 items
    - William O. Burr from William Burr, 1910, 1912; 4 items
    - William O. Burr from Sarah B. Gruman, 1915, 1921; 2 items
    - William O. Burr from Frederick A. Burr, et al., 1921
    - William O. Burr from Annie B. Cole, 1921
    - William O. Burr from Mary Burr Hawley, 1921
    - William O. Burr from Harriet B. Sargent, 1921
    - William O. Burr from Louise B. Polk, 1921
    - Frederick A. Burr from William O. Burr, 1927
    - Theodore B. Burr from Julius Newbauer, 1928
    - Theodore B. Burr from John and Molly Szalaye, 1930, 1933; 2 items
    - Raymonde P. Burr from Theodore B. Burr, 1938
    - Theodore B. Burr from New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad, 1949, 1950; 20 items
    - Theodore B. Burr from W. Eben Burr, 1854
    - Theodore B. Burr from Raymonde P. Burr, 1954
    - Theodore B. Burr from Brewster and Betsy Bullard, 1955
  - Probate Papers, 1827-1924; Folder E; 27 items
    - Catherine Burr, 1914-1915; 2 items
    - David Burr, 1827
    - David A. Burr, 1923-1924; 24 items
  - Probate Papers of David A. Burr, 1923-1924; Folder F; 10 items
  - Probate Papers of David A. Burr, 1923-1924; Folder G; 12 items
  - Probate Papers, 1810-1927; Folder H; 27 items
    - Ebenezer Burr, 1875-1876; 16 items
    - Ebenezer Burr, 1835; 2 items
    - Emma Josephine Burr, 1927
    - George Burr, 1812, 1814, 1817; 3 items
    - Hepzibah Burr, 1809-1818; 4 items
    - James Burr, 1927
    - Justus Burr, 1810
    - Ozias Burr, 1834
  - Probate Papers of William Burr, 1902, 1914, 1915; Folder I; 61 items
  - Photocopies of Probate Papers (incomplete): Thaddeus Burr and his wife Eunice Dennie Burr from the CT State Library, 1806; Folder J; 43 items
  - Writs, 1771-1911; Folder K; 18 items
    - Ephraim Burr, Jr. vs. Lothrop Lewis
    - Thaddeus Burr vs. Edmond Barlow
    - William Pixley vs. Thaddeus Burr
    - Thaddeus Burr vs. Pinkney Dimon
    - Peter Burr vs. Ezra Wheeler
    - Thaddeus Burr vs. Adam Babcock
    - Daniel Burr vs. Ebenezer Hubble
    - Ebenezer Burr vs. Edward Freeman
    - Seth Webb (estate) vs. Talcott Burr
    - John Burr vs. Joseph Wakeman
    - Nathaniel Bulkley vs. Turney Bulkley
    - Samuel Burr III vs. Thomas Nash
    - Eunice Burr vs. George Cable
    - George Burr vs. Jonathan Sturges
    - David S. Burr vs. Saugatuck Lodge
    - Oliver Huff vs. N.Y., N.H. and Hartford Railroad Co., David A. Burr, witness
- Box II--Papers belonging to assorted family members, 11 folders
  - Thaddeus Burr (1735-1801), 1752-1829; Folder A; 8 items
    - Letter to John Dennie, 1774
    - Letter to John Hancock, 1782
    - Letter to Doctor Francis Bowes Sayre, 1798; 3 items
    - Indenture between Thaddeus Burr and Nathan Hubbell, 1752
    - Payment to Thaddeus Burr from Colony Treasury, 1774
    - Thaddeus Burr's (son of Peter Burr) tax appeal, 1829
  - George Burr (b. 1740), 1808, 1812; Folder B; 6 items
    - Letter from Increase Sturges
    - Letter from David Burr
    - Bills
  - Peter Burr (1754-1816), Folder C
    - Farm and store account book (photocopy) with index, 1770-1779
  - Ebenezer Burr III (b. 1750's), Folder D; 5 items
    - Wine licenses, 1795-1979
    - Promissory note, 1787
  - Nathaniel Burr Jr. (b. 1767), Folder E; 2 items
    - Custodianship of his affairs by the Selectman of Fairfield, 1823
    - Zalmon Burr (1869-1832) county surveyor's certificate, 1814
  - Caroline Burr (b. 1798) book, 1811; Folder F
  - Eben Burr (1798-1873), Folder G; 6 items
    - Building price list for house, 254 N. Benson Rd., 1821
    - Cider Mill patent papers to Joseph Sturges and Eben Burr, 1830
    - Eben Burr's envelopes and scrap
  - David Burr (1826-1866) Letters to William Burr, 1849-1857; Folder H; 16 items
  - David Burr (1826-1866) Letters, 1847-1850; Folder I; 8 items
  - David Burr (1826-1866) school papers, n.d.; Folder J; 5 items
  - Unidentified bills, 1786-1822; Folder K; 4 items
- Box III--David Burr books, 2 folders
  - Books belonging to David Burr (Italian grammar), 1850's; Folder A; 4 items
  - Books belonging to David Burr (Italian and Spanish grammar), 1850's; Folder B; 4 items
- Box IV--Seafaring papers, 3 Folders
  - Miscellaneous papers, Folder A
    - Astronomical ephemeris, 1855; 4 items
    - Sailing directions, 1855; 2 items
    - Nautical almanac, 1856
  - Bowditch's Practical Navigator, 1807; Folder B
  - Books for use of crew and passengers, 1850; Folder C; 2 items
- Box V--David Burr papers, 5 folders
  - David Burr, 1850's; Folder A; 6 items
    - Books belonging to David Burr
    - Books and papers belonging to Mrs. David Burr
  - David Burr school books, 1850's; Folder B
  - David Burr, Folder C
    - Books belonging to David Burr
    - Books and papers belonging to Mrs. David Burr
    - Mrs. David Burr (Magdalen Grostephen, 1831-1908) Bible and religious books, 1840's, 1874; 3 items
  - Magdalen Burr bills and papers, 1890-1913; Folder D; 35 items
  - Magdalen Burr books and papers, sympathy letters, 1901; Folder E
- Box VI--William Burr papers, 8 folders
  - Account books and Produce sales, 1862-1890; Folder A; 18 items
  - Account books, 1863-1880; Folder B; 7 items
  - Books, Folder C
    - Account book and diaries, 1865-1919; 3 items
    - Fairfield Middle School, 1865
    - Cow account books, 1873-1879; 2 items
  - Bills and bills receipted, 1841-1906; Folder D; 36 items
  - Bills and bills receipted for house on Elm St., 1858-1862; Folder E; 41 items
  - Contracts and permits, Folder F
    - Great Eastern Fertilizer Co. contract, 1892
    - Bulletin Sign Board permit to Morse Bros., Canton, MA, 1906; 2 items
  - Letters, Folder G
    - from California, 1852-1856; 24 items
    - from David Hayes, 1853, 1883; 2 items
  - Surety bond and Elm St. house costs, 1891, n.d.; Folder H; 2 items
- Box VII--James O. Burr papers, 10 folders
  - Letters from unidentified woman, 1881-1882; Folder A; 23 items
  - Letters from Mame (b. 8 Oct. 1871), 1891-1892; Folder B; 13 items
  - Letters from Mame, 1893; Folder C; 42 items
  - Letters from Mame, 1-6, 1894; Folder D; 23 items
  - Letters from Mame, 7-12, 1894; Folder E; 17 items
  - Letters from Mame, 1895; Folder F; 35 items
  - Letters from Mame, 1896; Folder G; 23 items
  - Letters from Mame, n.d.; Folder H; 46 items
  - Miscellaneous papers, Folder I; 11 items
    - Letters and material from the Fairfield Rubber Co., 1884; 6 items
    - Sympathy letters, 1908; 2 items
    - Bill, Baptismal paper, Diary, 1893, 1878, n.d.
  - Loose stamps and covers with evaluations, 1890's; Folder J; 20 items
- Box VIII--James O. Burr Books
  - Bible and Scripture dictionary, 1869; Folder A; 2 items
  - Scripture and songbooks, 1870's and n.d.; Folder B; 5 items
  - School books, 1850, 1870, n.d.; Folder C
  - School books, 1870's, 1880's; Folder D; 3 items
- Box IX--Josie and David A. Burr, 2 folders
  - Emma Josephine Burr (1860-1901) scripture and songbook, 1850's, 1860's; Folder A; 2 items
  - David A. Burr (1864-1923) papers, Folder B
    - Bills and bills receipted, 0188-1891; 8 items
    - Bank books and checks, 1905-1922; 25 items
    - B.P.O. Elks & F. of A. passbooks, 1889, 1911; 2 items
    - Letters, 1920's; 12 items
- Box X--William O. Burr, 8 folders
  - Fairfield Tercentenary papers, 1938-1939; Folder A; 39 items
  - Fairfield Tercentenary papers, 1938; Folder B; 56 items
  - First Church of Christ Papers, 1930-1950; Folder C; 35 items
  - Bills and bills receipted, 1919, 1940's; Folder D; 10 items
  - Remodeling 254 N. Benson Rd. house plans, 1894; Folder E; 10 items
  - Letters and financial statements, 1914, 1940's; Folder F; 12 items
  - Phrenological character of W. O. Burr, programs and pamphlets, 1887, 1900's; Folder G; 21 items
  - Papers presented by W. O. Burr, 1933, n.d.; Folder H; 3 items
- Box XI--William O. Burr books and diaries, 6 folders
  - Travel diaries, 1889, 1941; Folder A; 2 items
  - Fairfield diary, 1929-1938; Folder B
  - Fairfield diary, 1939-1945; Folder C
  - Fairfield diary, 1946-1951; Folder D
  - Loose diary papers, 1946-1951; Folder E; 18 items
  - Rental books, farm account book, 1895-1934; Folder F; 4 items
- Box XII--Aretta Burr Sherwood, Eunice Dennie Burr and Harry Hill Sherwood papers, 10 folders
  - Letters to Aretta Burr Sherwood from H. H. Sherwood, 1918; Folder A; 21 items
  - Letters to Aretta Burr Sherwood from H. H. Sherwood, 1918; Folder B; 42 items
  - Letters to Aretta Burr Sherwood from H. H. Sherwood, 1918-1919; Folder C; 43 items
  - Letters from H. H. Sherwood to Eunice Burr, 1918; Folder D; 28 items
  - Diary of H. H. Sherwood in France with YMCA, 1919; Folder E
  - Aretta Burr Sherwood diary, 1929; Folder F
  - Aretta Burr Sherwood diary, 1931; Folder G
  - Aretta Burr Sherwood diary, 1932-1944; Folder H
  - Eunice Burr diary, 1915-1919; Folder I
  - Miscellaneous clippings, Folder J; 15 items
- Box XIII--Lillian Burr's Mt. Holyoke College Papers, class of 1905, 8 folders, 500 items
- Box XIV--Lillian Burr papers, 6 folder
  - College papers, Folders A & B; 80 items
  - Letters, Folders C & D; 49 items
  - Letters from W. H. Burr, Folder E; 27 items
  - Business letters to Lillian Burr, Folder F; 17 items
- Box XV--Florence Burr papers, 8 folders
  - School class notes, n.d.; Folders A & B; 10 items
  - Patterns and transfers, Folder C; 22 items
  - Handwritten recipe book, Folder D
  - Letterheads and envelopes, Folder E; 13 items
  - Letter to Lillie, 1894; Folder F
  - Morris Lyon Burr's Yale Class Day book and Manual of the First Church of Christ, 1905, 1881; Folder G
  - Jennings family photos, Folder H; 13 items
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also Oversize MSS Box 1
- Box XVI--Theodore B. Burr, Raymonde Pezard Burr and Theodosia Burr papers, 10 folders
  - Schools books, 1914-1915; Folder A; 3 items
  - Business papers, 1939-1940; Folder B; 23 items
  - War ration books, World War I certificate, liquor permit and misc., 1920's-1940; Folder C; 81 items
  - Postcards, 1917-1940; Folder D; 8 items
  - R. P. Burr's war rations, stock certificates and citizenship certificate, 1917, 1931; Folder E; 7 items
  - Theodosia Burr Thomas Lyon papers; letter to Alice Burr from her mother, 1920, 1930's and 1940's; Folder F
  - Photographs and clips of Jean Parkermege (Lyon), 1940's; Folder G; 8 items
  - Miscellaneous papers, Folder H; 21 items
  - Newspaper clips, 1941, 1945; Folder I; 3 items
  - Photographs, Folder J; 3 items
- Box XVII--Miscellaneous papers, 7 folders
  - Letters to Florence A. Wright from "Da Da" while in the theatre with the Elsie DeWolf Company, 1901-1902; Folder A; 12 items
  - Eben Burr's Bible and passport book, 1908, 1924; Folder B; 2 items
  - Letters to Dr. Childs from Anna F. Burr, 1904; Folder C; 2 items
  - Reminiscences of Fairfield of C. H. Phelps, 1940; Folder D; 3 items
  - Genealogy notes, Folder E; 40 items
  - Newspaper clips, Folder F; 17 items
  - Newspaper clips, 1844, 1927; Folder G; 2 items
- Box XVIII--Account books (owner unknown), 2 folders
  - Checkbooks and account books, 1912-1915; Folder A; 8 items
  - Brewery sales book, Folder B; 5 items
- Box XIX--Burr Family photographs and postcards, 10 folders
  - Burr family photographs, Folders A-I; 90 items
  - Postcards, 1919-1922; Folder B; 60 items
- Box XX--Howard Burr Papers, 4 folders; The papers in this box are copies.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition note
  Papers from this box come from L87.July.8
  - General Assembly resolution, Southport boundaries, 1832; Folder A; 3 items
  - Ephraim Burr papers, Folder B; 39 items
    - Indenture papers, 1814-1831; 6 items
    - Land deeds, 1819-1836; 9 items
    - Certificates as Seaman, State Militia, 1820; 2 items
    - Papers re: Ship Camden, 1849-1863; 5 items
    - Letters from John Gould Jennings to Ephraim Burr, 1862; 5 items
    - Ephraim Burr will, 1883; 4 items
    - Will and inventory of Frances, 1900; 6 items
  - Peter Burr papers, Folder C; 23 items
    - Deed-Peter Burr from Ephraim and Abigail Burr, 1776
    - Peter Burr will and estate distribution, 1812, 1816; 18 papers
    - Esther Burr (wife of Peter) will, 1822
    - Ebenezer Burr (brother of Peter) will, 1820; 3 items
  - Henry S. Burr papers, Folder D; 47 items
    - School paper
    - Journal of sailing trip from N.Y.C. to S.A. with typed copy, 1849; 26 items
    - Letters, 1853, 1857, 1863, 1870; 12 items
    - Will, 1871; 8 items
- Box XXI--Mrs. Frank A. Burr papers, 6 folders
  - Letters, 1920's; Folder A
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1910-1929; Folder B
  - Wednesday afternoon Music Club, 1907-1927; Folder C
  - Bank books, 1927-1930; Folder D
  - Photographs, Folder E
    - F. A. Burr, 8 items
    - Mrs. F. A. Burr, 3 items
    - Assorted Burrs, Lyons, Hawleys and Grummans, 24 items
  - Photographs, Folder F
    - 4-H Club, 11 items
    - Trowel Club outing, 1 item
    - Masonic Lodge, 2 items
    - Town basketball team, 1934-1935; 1 item
    - unidentified, 12 items
- Box XXII--William T. Burr papers, 7 folders
  - Bills, 1930-1939; Folder B
  - Bills, 1930-1939; Folder B
  - Letters, 1920-1929; Folder C
  - Civil Air Patrol papers, 1940-1949; Folder D
  - Checkbook and Police manual, 1920; Folder E
  - 4-H Park papers, 1970-1979; Folder F
  - Photographs, circa 1950; Folder G
- Box XXIII--Fred A. Burr papers/Miscellaneous, 6 items
  - Fred A. Burr papers, 1917-1918; Folder A
  - Fred A. Burr papers, Folder B
  - Police department newsclips, 1931; Folder C
  - Frank B. Taylor's detective papers, 1879-1884; Folder D
  - Miscellaneous papers, Folder E
  - Miscellaneous papers, Folder F
- Oversize Item A: Alva Burr's Day book, 2/6/1802-3/8/1802
- Oversize Item B: Nehemiah Burr's Account book, 1757-1788
- Oversize Item C: Store Account book of William Burr, 1762-1769
  Given by Dr. David H. Burr, President of the Aaron Burr Association, 1987, in honor of Dr. Samuel Engle Burr, Jr. (L88.Jan.1)
- Oversize Item D: James Burr's Seamen's Friend Society, 1878
- Oversize Item E: David A Burr's Deputy Sherriff certificate, 1907
- Oversize item F: Lillian Burr's topographic maps and Westporter Herald, 1902
- Oversize Item G: Theodore B. Burr's grammar school diploma, 1914
- Oversize Item H: Map of Pine Creek, Fairfield, n.d.
- Oversize item I: A general chart of the Mediterranean, Adriatic, Black Seas and Greacian Archipelago owned by David Burr, 1830, 1844-1849
- Oversize Item J: Photographs
  From L94.Oct.9